Guide to the Yevgeny Yevtushenko Papers M1088
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Manuscripts, Series 3.
  - Subseries 3. Prose
    - Konets Mushketerov: contracts, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      Letter from Nikola Karraro, President Aktsionernogo Obshchestva "N'iu Tim", typescript, 5 p., 1985 June 24. Contract with Aktsionernoe Obshchestvo "N'iu Tim", typescript, 10 p., 1985 June 24. Fragment of contract with Aktsionernoe Obshchestvo "N'iu Tim", typescript, 5 p,, 1985 June 24. Contract with "New Team", Copy of typescript (in English), 5 p., n.d. "Dogovor" with "N'iu Tim", copy of typescript, 5 p., 1985 Oct. 5. Fragment, copy of typescript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Konets Mushketerov: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
      Tsenarii, excerpt from journal "Iskusstvo kino", 31 p., 1988. Plan du Chateau de Vianden, flyer, 1 p., 1983 July. Copy of handwritten draft fragment, 2 p., n.d. Handwritten drafts, signed, 3 p., n.d.
    - Korni i Vetvi, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
      Copy of typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Kradenye Iabloki: Table of Contents, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
      "Stolen Apples". Copy of typescript (in English), 7 p., n.d.
    - Lady Don Quixote, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Typescript (in English), 2 p.
    - Lebed' s razryblennym gorlom, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
      Copy of typescript, 3 p., signed, n.d.
    - Leningrad, undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Typescript, fragment, 5 p., n.d.
    - Malen'koe, no tiazhkoe znamia, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Copy of typescript, fragment, 2 p., n.d.
    - Mertvye sramu ne imut, undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Copy of typescript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Mezhdu buduschim i proshlym [Between the Future and the Past], undated (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Typescript of fragments, 17 p., n.d. Annotated typescript in English, 9 p. n.d.
    - Mir, podarennyi nam, undated (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - My - Odno tseloe, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
      Copy of typescript, 6 p., n.d.
    - My Russia, undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
      "Plane Stopped in the Sky; First - a few words about the Georgians." Copy of annotated and signed typescript, 19 p., n.d.
    - Nasledie Gumileva [or Vozvrashchenie Gumileva?], undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
      Signed and annotated copy of typescript, 8 p., n.d.
    - Na smert' poeta Kaisyn Kuliev, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
      Signed typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Nature Demands Peace [about Paul Winter], 1985 January 30 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      Typescript of unedited translation into English by Albert C. Todd of article that appeared in Literaturnaia Gazeta, 1985 January 30; 7 p.
      Winter, Paul
    - Ne razluchaite pesen s vekom, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
      Copy of typescript, 5 p., n.d.
    - Nespravelivost' dazhe spravedlivoi smertnoi kazni, undated (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Ne umirai prezhde smerti: Chapters, undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Ne umirai prezhde smerti: Correspondence concerning publication of English version, 1993 - 1994 (Box 26, Folder 21)
      Numerous letters attempting to find a publisher for the English edition.
      Rhein, Hedy; Random House; Steimatzky, Eri M.; Simon & Schuster; Krupp, Carolyn; Korda, Michael; Mayer, Peter; Little, Brown and Company; Karp, Jonathan; Klebanoff, Arthur; Donald, Roger; Doubleday; Talese, Nan; Close, Ann; Straus, Roger; Congdon, Don; Alfred A. Knopf; The Penguin Group; Bouis, Nina
    - Ne umirai prezhde smerti: English Flap Copy, 1995 Feb. 9 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      Faxcopy, 1 p., 1995 Feb. 9
    - Ne umirai prezhde smerti: Introduction to a reading of a chapter, undated (Box 26, Folder 23)
      Annotated typescript, 3 p., n.d. Copy of typescript, 3 p., n.d.
    - Ne umirai prezhde smerti: advertising, undated (Box 26, Folder 24)
      Includes Europaverlag catalogs.
    - Ne umirai prezhde smerti: Book covers, undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Nezpiatnannoe pokolenie, undated (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Nezhnost' sostradaniia, undated (Box 26, Folder 27)
      Copy of typescript, 2 p., n.d. Fragment, copy of signed typescript, 2 p., n.d. Handwritten draft, 1 p., n.d.
    - Nezhnost' i zhizhni [about Vladimir Sokolov], undated (Box 26, Folder 28)
      Handwritten drafts, some signed, 14 p., n.d.
    - Nobody is Swimming Alone, 1995 Oct. 21 (Box 26, Folder 29)
      Signed typescript, 3 p., 1995 Oct. 21.
      Keeney, Patricia
    - Nochevala tuchka zolataia, undated (Box 26, Folder 30)
      "Vrezka k otryvku iz povesti Anatoliia Pristavkina;" Copy of signed typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Novyi poet (o rasskazakh v stikhakh Vadima Antonova), 1988 Sept. 26 (Box 26, Folder 31)
      Copy of typescript, 2 p., 1988 Sept. 26
    - Obrechennyi na bessmertie, 1997 Apr. - Nov. (Box 26, Folder 32)
      Signed typescript, 15 p., 1997 Apr. - Nov.
    - The "Omm-issar of American Poetry" [i.e. Allen Ginsberg], undated (Box 26, Folder 33)
      Typescript (in English), 4 p., n.d.
      Bouis, Antonina W.; Ginsberg, Allen
    - On Charity between Countries, undated (Box 26, Folder 34)
      Handwritten draft (in English), 1 p., n.d.
    - O natsional'nom takte, undated (Box 26, Folder 35)
      Annotated copy of typescripts, signed, 6 p., n.d.
    - O premii Borisu Pasternaku, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 36)
      Signed typescript and copy of typescript of article published in "Novoe Vremia", no. 1, 1988; 4 p. ea.
    - Osiazanie slukhom, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 37)
      Copy of typescript, "Talant est' chudo nesluchainoe", 5 p., 1976.
    - Ostorozhnei s balkanam!: New York, 1999 Apr. 17 - 1999 Apr. 20 (Box 26, Folder 38)
      Two signed typescripts, 5 p. each, 1999 Apr. 17 - 20.
    - Otpechatan material dlia knigi izdatel'stva APN, undated (Box 26, Folder 39)
      List of material, copy of typescript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Ottsom ne skazannoe slovo: k vykhodu dvukhtomnika Ivan Tarba, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 40)
      Copy of typescript article published in "Sov. Abkhaziia," 4 p., 1981.
    - Otvety na voprosy kommissii "Irdis", undated (Box 26, Folder 41)
      Signed typescript, 4 p., July 19 [no year]
    - Pamiat' - eto tozhe meditsina, undated (Box 26, Folder 42)
      (Article for "Iunost'"; copy of typescript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Parodiia, kak sredstvo vospitaniia, undated (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Pasternak ob iskusstve, 1966 July 3 (Box 26, Folder 44)
      Copy of typescript, 31 p., 1966 July 3.
    - Pechal'no, no tverdo, undated (Box 26, Folder 45)
      Copy of annotated and signed typescript, 3 p., n.d.
    - Pervoe sobranie sochinenie v vos'mi tomakh: list, undated (Box 26, Folder 46)
      Handwritten [by Masha Yevtushenko?] list of works, 3 p., n.d.
    - Pervye pevtsi svobody, undated (Box 26, Folder 47)
      Copy of typescript, 17 p., n.d.
    - Pidzhak ottuda, 1999 May 24 (Box 26, Folder 48)
      Faxcopy, 5 p., 1999 May 24
    - Pis'mo Sovetskim Teleradioslushateliam, 1974 Feb. 16 (Box 26, Folder 49)
      Multiple fragments of copies of typescripts, 7 p., 1974 Feb. 16
    - Platonov: Articles, undated (Box 26, Folder 50)
      "Gosudarstvennyi zhitel';" annotated typescript, 16 p., n.d. "Platonov o literature;" typescript, 3 p., n.d. Fragment, signed typescript, 7 p., n.d.
    - Pocherk, Pokhozhii na zhuravlei, undated (Box 26, Folder 51)
      Photocopy of book excerpt, 3.5 p., n.d.
    - Podal'she ot tsarei!, undated (Box 26, Folder 52)
      Copy of typescript, 1 p., n.d. Copy of signed typscript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Poetry--The Mother of Human Subtlety (Commencement Keynote Speech at Juniata College, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 53)
      Signed typescript, 9 p., 1996.
    - Pod kozhei statui svobody, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
      Copy of typescript, 92 p., n.d.
    - Pod kozhei statui svobody: programs, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      Khar'kov, 1976. Moskovskii Teatr na Taganke, Moscow, n.d. Teatr Poezii, Erevan, n.d.
    - Podvig Bezdomnosti, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
      Typescript, 9 p., n.d.
    - Poet v Rossii bol'she, chem poet: TV series, 1995 - 1996 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      Plan to produce 52 26-minute programs each year for two year. Lists of themes. Typescript.
    - Poeziia - mat' chelovecheskoi tonkosti, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Poezii mozolistye ruki: Dialog: Yevgenii Yevtushenko - Otar Chiladze, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Poeziia - velikaia derzhava (antologiia sovremennoi russkoi poezii), undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Includes short biographies on Vladimir Sokolov, Aleksandr Mezhirov, Iurii Levitanskii, Iosif Brodskii, Aleksei Korovin. Typescript, 5 p., n.d.
    - Poiushchii umnii chelovek, 1998 Jan. 4 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      For cd of Mark Mernam [?], handwritten signed draft, 2 p., 1998 Jan. 4.
    - Pokhorony Stalina [originally called Trubnaia Ploshchad']: kinostsenarii [1 of 2], undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
      Copy of signed typescript, 77 p., n.d. Annotated typescript, p. 56 - 66, n.d.
    - Pokhorony Stalina [originally called Trubnaia Ploshchad']: kinostsenarii [2 of 2], undated (Box 27, Folder 10)
      Copy of signed typescript, 77 p., n.d.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: English Subtitles (Stalin's Funeral) [1 of 2], undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
      Two copies of annotated typescript, 40 p. (each), n.d.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: English Subtitles (Stalin's Funeral) [2 of 2], undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
      Copy of annotated typescript, 40 p., n.d.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: Rezhisserskii Stsenarii, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      Bound copy, 111 p., 1990.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: Correspondence, 1990 - 1991 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      Letter to Vladimir Dostal, General Director Mosfilm, from John Daly, Hemdale Film Corporation, concerning Hemadale's interest in international rights to "Stalin's Funeral", two copies, 1 p. (each), 1990 Apr. 30. Fax to John Daly from Vladimir Dostal replying to above-mentioned letter, 1 p., 1991 Jan. 30. Letter to Yevtushenko from Gilles Jacob, Festival International du Film, 1 p., 1991 Feb. 4
    - Pokhorony Stalina: Credits, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      Copy of typescript, original signature of director B. Vel'sher, 2 p., 1990.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: Scene by scene notes, p. 1 - 79, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
      Handwritten notes, 79 p., n.d.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: Scene by scene notes, p. 80 - 140, undated (Box 27, Folder 17)
      Handwritten notes, 81 p., n.d.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: Scene by scene notes, p. 141 - end, undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
      Handwritten notes, n.d.
    - Pokhorony Stalina: Flyers and posters, 1992 - 1993 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      The International Poetry Forum and Pittsburgh Filmmakers, 1992 Feb. 17. The National Leadership Council of The American Jewish Committee, 1992 Mar. 23. Lewis & Clark College and Portland State University, 1992 Apr. 24. Principal International, 1993 Mar. 1. The Museum of Modern Art, Department of Film, 1993 Dec. 21. XIX Moskovskogo Mezhdunarodnogo Kinofestivalia, n.d. The Law Firm of Kodner & Watkins, An Evening with "Zhenya", n.d. Rice Media Center, n.d. The Cincinnati-Kharkov Sister City Project, n.d. Mosfilm
    - Politika - Privelegiia Vsekh [also called "Propast' - v dva pryzhka?" ?], 1989 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      Copy of typescript of contents [?], 4 p., 1989. Copy of typescript, 1 p., n.d. Primechanie, typescript, 18 p., n.d. Copy of typescript, 22 p., n.d.
    - Pravo no syzhenie, Pravo na zashchitu, 1988 Apr. 8 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      Published in "Leninskaia pravda". Typescript, 4 p., 1988 Apr. 8. Copy of typescript, 4 p.
    - Predislovie k antologii Dzheffri Dattona [Foreword to Geoffrey Dutton anthology], undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Dutton, Geoffrey
    - Predislovie k dvukhtomnika "Izbrannaia Proza", undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Fragment, typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Predislovie k knige "1989" [?], 1990 May (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Signed copy of typescript, 2 p., 1990 May.
    - Predislovie k knige A. Bibina, ili Vystavke ili Katalogu (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Includes the poem "Pavlodar."
      Bibin, A.
    - Predislovie k knige "Izabrannye Stikhi", 1991 Jan. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Signed and annotated typescript, 2 p., 1991 Jan. Table of contents [?], handwritten draft, 1 p., n.d.
    - Predislovie k knige na uzbekskom iazyke, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Predislovie k poeme D. Kedrina "Khrustal'nyi ulei", undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Copy of signed typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Predrenessans sovetskogo iskusstva, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Copy of signed typescript, 6 p., n.d.
    - Predvybornaia Programma, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
      Annotated typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Prichastnost', undated (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Priperet' k stenke i postavit' v ugol?, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
      Copy of typescript, 2 p., n.d. Fragment, copy of typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Prirodnyi poet, undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
      Fragments, copies of typescripts, 7 p., n.d.
    - Proverka na chelovechnost', undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Retrospectivnye intrigi, undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
      Copy of typescript, 4 p., n.d.
    - Retsenziia po pros'be anonima, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Russia's Amateur Justice: Stetson Law Review, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      Journal reprint, 5 p., 1996 Summer. Faxcopy, 11 p., 1995 Oct. 27.
    - S blagodarnosti'iu, i vol'iu, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
      Typescript, 3 p., n.d. Copy of typescript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Script: Unidentified, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
      Typescript, 11 p., n.d.
    - S dushoiu- o strane dushi, undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
      Published in "Abkhaziia v russkoi literature", copy of typescript, 7 p., n.d.
    - Shcheli v Perrone, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 22)
      Typescript, 3 p., 1960
    - Siberia: a proposal by Yevtushenko and Boyd Norton, undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
      5 p.
    - Skol'zkaia Arbuznaia Korka: letter tot he editor, 1989 May 4 (Box 28, Folder 24)
      Annotated copy of typescript, 2 p., 1989 May 4.
    - Skomorokh i Bogatyr', undated (Box 28, Folder 25)
      Fragment, copy of typescript, 3 p., n.d.
    - Slovo o gruzinskoi poezii, undated (Box 28, Folder 26)
      Multiple copies of typescripts, n.d.
    - Slovo o Pushkine, undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
      Signed typescript, 3 p., n.d. Copy of typescript, 4 p., n.d.
    - Sokrovennoe - eto vse, undated (Box 28, Folder 28)
      Copy of typescript, 8 p., n.d.
    - Speech: Army in Lithuania, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 29)
      Handwritten draft, 3 p., ca. 1991
    - Speech: Memorial Service for Norman Cousins, 1991 Jan. 29 (Box 28, Folder 30)
      Two programs, one with handwritten notes.
    - Speech: Opening of Russian Film Festival, 1999 Dec. 10 (Box 28, Folder 31)
      Typescript, 3 p., 1999 Dec. 10
    - Speech: Rech' na s'ezde simpodume pisatelei - epokha perestroika, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 32)
      Signed handwritten drafts, fragments, 7 p., ca. 1985 Dec. 19; faxcopy of English translation printed in the New York Times, 2 p., 1985 Dec. 19.
    - Speech: Rech' na X s'ezde pisatelei Gruzii, 1986 May 24 (Box 28, Folder 33)
      Published in "Zaria Vostoka," copy of typescript, 5 p., 1986 May 24.
    - Speech: Rech' v Italii, undated (Box 28, Folder 34)
      Handwritten draft, 4 p., n.d.
    - Speech: Rech' v Kazakhstane, undated (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Speech: Rech' v Stokholme na PEN-Klube [Speech in Stokholm, PEN - Center], undated (Box 28, Folder 36)
      Copy of handwritten draft, 8 p., n.d.
    - Speech: Writer's Union Congress in Moscow, undated (Box 28, Folder 37)
      Typescripts and signed handwritten drafts, n.d.
    - Speeches: Unidentified, undated (Box 28, Folder 38)
      Typescripts and handwritten drafts, n.d.
    - Spitsyn, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 39)
      Typescript, 7 p., 1957
    - Stories - Rasskazy, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 40)
      Russian Study Series No. 59, Russian Language Specialties, Bilingual, 1966.
    - Strakh Glasnosti, undated (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Svobodnyi Katorzhnik (about Ancel Nunn), undated (Box 28, Folder 42)
      Tyepscript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Toska po novoi filosofii, 1994 Sept. 26 (Box 28, Folder 43)
      Handwritten draft (including letter addressed to Kirsten Mikkelsen), 11 p., 1994 Sept, 26
    - Tot, kto znatok v liubvi - liubvi ne znaet, undated (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Transcript of BBC radio program about Yevtushenko and Voznesenskii, 1987 Aug. 20 (Box 28, Folder 45)
      Kaleidoscope with Mark Steyn, typescript, 7 p., 1987 Aug. 20.
      Steyn, Mark; BBC; Voznesenskīĭ, Andreĭ
    - Tretii vybor: New York, 1999 Apr. 9 (Box 28, Folder 46)
      Signed typescript, 4 p., 1999 Apr. 9.
    - Tribute to Robert Donaldson, 1996 Apr. 24 (Box 28, Folder 47)
      Flyer, 1 p., 1996 Apr., 24. Handwritten drafts, 3 p., n.d.
      Donaldson, Robert
    - Ukhodit istoriia literatury, undated (Box 28, Folder 48)
    - Uskorenie spravedlivosti, undated (Box 28, Folder 49)
    - Vdokhnovenie, i kal'kuliatsiia, undated (Box 28, Folder 50)
    - Velikie zaveshchaiut bor'bu, undated (Box 28, Folder 51)
      Published in "Talant est' chudo nesluchainoe", copy of typescript, 1 p., n.d.
    - Vernut' premiiu Pasternaku, undated (Box 28, Folder 52)
      Copy of typescript, 3 p., n.d.
    - Veselye prikliucheniia, ili tragediia?, undated (Box 28, Folder 53)
    - Vybros'te ad iz golovy..., 1998 Sept. 4 - Nov. 3 (Box 28, Folder 54)
      Signed typescript, 20 p., 1998 Sept. 4 - Nov. 3; Annotated and signed typescript, 19 p., 1998 Sept. 4 - Nov. 3.
    - Speech: Association of Russian Language Teachers, 1998 Oct. 17 (Box 28, Folder 55)
    - Vmesto pozdravleniia, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Vzletov s ladoni Maiakovskogo, 1982 July 8 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      Printed in "Molodezh' Gruzii", copy of typescript, 4 p., 1982 July 8.
    - Vstavki k predisloviiu: Izbrannoe N. Glazkova, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
      Glazkova, N.
    - Vossozdanie golosa, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Signed typescript, 2 p., n.d.
    - Vypiska dlia stat'i o Kunleve, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Vystuplenie v teleperedache ob Eduarde Kolmanovskom [Presentation of TV program about Eduard Kolmanovski], undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Kolmanovskii, Eduard
    - When Divorce is Impossible [about Melvin Mordecai Wilk], 1994 Mar. 8 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Signed faxcopy, 2 p., 1994 Mar. 8
      Wilk, Melvin Mordecai
    - Yevtushenko and Allen Ginsberg Converse: transcript, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
      Typescript, 27 p., n.d.
    - Zabotnaia pokhodka, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
      Typescript and copy of typescript, 3 p. each, n.d.
    - Zakhodi, u menia est' dzhondzholi, 1997 June 16 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      Typescript, 10 p., 1997 June 16.
    - Zapiski s Giagosi Teti Iry, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
      Handwritten draft, 2 p., n.d. (Tetia Ira)
    - Zashchita sobstvennoi dushi (predislovie k knige stikhov G. Aigi), 1988 Sept. 26 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      Copy of typescript, 2 p., 1988 Sept. 26.
    - Zelenaia Kalitka: iz vystupleniia na obsuzhenii gruzinskoi poezii v SP SSR, 1958 Mar. 28 (Box 29, Folder 13)
      Copy of typescript, 1 p., 1958 Mar. 28.
    - Zhizn' prekrasna i besposhchadna (Perechityvaia Marka Avreliia), undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Zhurnalizm obygryvaet literaturu: Draft for speech, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
      Fragments, copies of typescripts, 5 p., n.d.
    - "Zima" trevogi nashei, 1988 Apr. 6 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      Printed in "Literaturnaia gazeta," typescript, 3 p., 1988 Apr. 6.
    - Zrenie Serdtsa, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      Printed in " Talant est' chudo nesluchainoe". Copy of typescript, 6 p., 1974.
    - Typescript of published articles, reviews, etc. [1 of 3], 1966 - 1973 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      Copy of typescript.
    - Typescript of published articles, radiobroadcasts,etc. [2 of 3], 1965 - 1973 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Typescript of published articles, interviews, broadcasts, etc. [3 of 3], 1965 - 1973 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Antologiia Russkoi Poezii Dvadtsatogo Veka, undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
      Contents, annotated copy of typescript, 11 p., n.d. Commentary on included authors, annotated copy of typescript, 19 p., n.d. Commentary on included authors, copy of typescript, 18 p., n.d. Handwritten draft, fragment, 1 p., n.d. Note to Ellen from Vera Chalidze, 1975 May 28. Additions to the Russian Anthology, typescript, 1975 May. Handwritten notes [by A. Mezhirov?], 3 p., n.d. Handwritten letter to Yevtushenko from A. Mezhirov [?], 4 p., n.d. "Posledniaia glavka antologii," handwritten draft, 1 p., n.d. "Ot sostavitelia," copy of typescript, 3 p., n.d.
      Mezhirov, A.
    - Antologiia Russkoi Poezii Dvadtsatogo Veka: Biographies, undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
      Typescripts and handwritten drafts, 25 p., n.d.
    - Antologiia Russkoi Poezii Dvadtsatogo Veka: Poet i istoriia [Foreword], undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
      Copy of typescript, 35 p., n.d. Copy of typescript, 9 p., n.d.
    - Antologiia Russkoi Poezii Dvadtsatogo Veka: Predislovie [Foreword], 1974 (Box 29, Folder 24)
      Typescript, 26 p., 1974
    - Antologiia Russkoi Poezii Dvadtsatogo Veka [Foreword], undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
      [in English] Copy of typescript, 32 p., n.d. [in Russian] fragment; copy of typescript, 18 p., n.d. [in Russian] fragment, copy of typescript, 16 p., n.d. fragments, copies of typescripts, 3 p., n.d.
    - Antologiia Russkoi Poezii Dvadtsatogo Veka (advertising), undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
      Three brochures, n.d.
    - Kazhdyi chelovek - Superderzhava (radiop'esa), undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
      Copy of typescript, 29 p., n.d. Signed typescript [entitled "Oni mogli menia ubit'"], 18 p. n.d. Copy of typescript [entitled "Kazhdyi chelovek - sverkhderzhava"], 26 p., n.d.
    - Piat' uslovii Pablo Nerudy, 1995 Feb. 7 (Box 29, Folder 28)
      Faxcopy of signed typescript, 11 p., 1995 Feb. 7.
      Neruda, Pablo
    - Suffering Cannot be Foreign, undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
      Copy of annotated typescript, 21 p., n.d.
    - Miscellaneous Fragments [1 of 7], undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments [2 of 7], undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments [3 of 7], undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments [4 of 7], undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments [5 of 7], undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments [6 of 7], undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Fragments [7 of 7], undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Fragments in English, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Detskii Sad: Filmstrip (Box 78.1, Folder 7)
    - "Babii Yar in Manhattan"/"Cranes still fly", 2001 Sep. (Box 89, Folder 1)
      Varios signed typescripts 2001 Sep.
    - "Dona Quijote", screenplay, undated (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - "Essay about Shostakovich'", 1962-2000 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      Typescript, 27p., 1962-2000
    - "Gorech a ne torzhestvo (Yeltsin i russkaya intelligentsya)", 1999, Jan. 4 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      Signed typescript, 5p., 1999 Jan. 4; signed handwritten fragment, 1p., 1999 Jan. 4.
    - "If all danes were Jews", undated (Box 89, Folder 5)
      Play (in Russian).
    - "If all danes were Jews", undated (Box 89, Folder 6)
      Play (in English).
    - Interview with "Bulevard", undated (Box 89, Folder 7)
      Signed typescript, 13p., n. d.
    - Interview with "IndyVestnik", 1997-98 (Box 89, Folder 8)
      Photocopy, 3p., 1997-98
    - Interview with "Izvestya", 2001 Nov. 6 (Box 89, Folder 9)
      Signed typescript, 6p., 2001 Nov. 6
    - Interview with "Sovetskii Sport", 1999 Jan. (Box 89, Folder 10)
      Signed typescript, 4p., 1999 Jan.
    - Interview with "Die Woche", May 6 (Box 89, Folder 11)
      Signed typescript, 7p., (?) May 6.
    - Introduction to "One Day in the Life of Ivan Denisovich", undated (Box 89, Folder 12)
      Fragments, handwritten draft, 11p., n. d. Includes letter from Yevtushenko to Serebrinskaya, Yulia.
    - "Pamyatnik iz muziki", 2001 Nov. 4 (Box 89, Folder 13)
      Signed typescript, 4p., 2001 Nov. 4.
    - "Pontifikatori", 2000 Sep. 11 (Box 89, Folder 14)